<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>French on </title>
    <link>/tags/french/</link>
    <description>Recent content in French on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/french/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PLS et PLS sparse</title>
      <link>/teaching/spls_cm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/spls_cm/</guid>
      <description>Overview The PLS tool is powerfull to tackle the curse of dimensionality, especially if the dataset suffers form high colinearities or if $n&amp;lt;p$. It even works when the response matrix is multivariate!
That course, given to M2-biostatistics students of ISPED, website introduces that tool and its sparse version thanks to which this is easily possible to select variables.
Magistral course  Recalls over linear regression and non-invertible cases,
 PLS1 and PLS2 algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maths and function analysis</title>
      <link>/teaching/double_cursus_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/double_cursus_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Overview The Health and Science is established since 2107 and proposes to the students of second year medical studies, pharmacology and odontology an early formation to research.
Current Course  Introduction to noisy and uncertain models.
 Recalls on function analysis, derivation rules and extrematlity conditions. Basis functions (exponential, logarithm, trigonometric).
 Introduction to Ordinary Differential Equations (ODE).
 Case study: The fall of an apple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maths and linear algebra</title>
      <link>/teaching/double_cursus_analysis_algebre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/double_cursus_analysis_algebre/</guid>
      <description>Overview The Health and Science is established since 2107 and proposes to the students of second year medical studies, pharmacology and odontology an early formation to research.
Course  Physical problem example: two weights bound with a spring. System of two bounded ordinary differntial equations (EDO). Solution with no linear algebra general theory.
 Linear algebra discovering: vectors, matrices, basis operations: sum, product, trace, determinant, inverse. Notions of free family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics and Probability</title>
      <link>/teaching/double_cursus_stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/double_cursus_stats/</guid>
      <description>Overview The Health and Science is established since 2107 and proposes to the students of second year medical studies, pharmacology and odontology an early formation to research.
Course  Introduction to statistical language and notions such as event, incompatibility or independancy.
 Enumerations and Bayes formula
 Classical estimators (mean, variance)
 Usual discret and continuous laws.
 An introduction to the statistical tests.
  
Practical work on Python  Statistical tests and multiplicity: Unitary tests, boxplot visualisations, Bonferroni and Benjamini-Hochberg corrections</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>