<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on </title>
    <link>/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Maths and function analysis</title>
      <link>/teaching/double_cursus_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/double_cursus_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Course:  Introduction to noisy and uncertain models.
 Recalls on function analysis, derivation rules and extrematlity conditions. Basis functions (exponential, logarithm, trigonometric).
 Introduction to Ordinary Differential Equations (ODE).
 Case study: The fall of an apple.
  
Practical work, Python:  General Introduction: to the language and its main data variable structures plus example of bivariate scatterplot visualisation 
 Gradient Descent: A light study of the algorithm for a real valued function of a single real variable and presentation of the performances</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maths and linear algebra</title>
      <link>/teaching/double_cursus_analysis_algebre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/double_cursus_analysis_algebre/</guid>
      <description>Course:  Physical problem example: two weights bound with a spring. System of two bounded ordinary differntial equations (EDO). Solution with no linear algebra general theory.
 Linear algebra discovering: vectors, matrices, basis operations: sum, product, trace, determinant, inverse. Notions of free family. Diagonalisation.
 Two applied examples:
 Square inverse problem (as much equations as variables): solution with matrix inversion. Solve a system of coupled linear EDO thanks to diagonalisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics and Probability</title>
      <link>/teaching/double_cursus_stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/double_cursus_stats/</guid>
      <description>Course:  Introduction to statistical language and notions such as event, incompatibility or independancy.
 Enumerations and Bayes formula
 Classical estimators (mean, variance)
 Usual discret and continuous laws.
 An introduction to the statistical tests.
  
Practical work, Python:  Statistical tests and multiplicity: Unitary tests, boxplot visualisations, Bonferroni and Benjamini-Hochberg corrections 
 Linear regression: Python linear regression tools 
 Newton-Raphson algorithm for likelihood maximization: Study of this algorithm for a real valued function depending on 2 variables</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>